THE CONSTITUTION OF JAPAN ARTICLE 24
（日本宪法第二十四条）
MARRIAGE SHALL BE BASED ONLY ON THE MUTUAL CONSENT OF BOTH SEXES
（婚姻必须建立在 男女双方同意的基础上）
AND IT SHALL BE MAINTAINED THROUGH MUTUAL COOPERATION
（必须在夫妻享有 平等权利的基础上）
WITH THE EQUAL RIGHTS OF HUSBAND AND WIFE AS A BASIS.
（通过双方相互合作来维持）
Here.
给
Thank you.
谢谢
Can I clean this up?
我可以把这些收拾掉吗？
Please.
拜托了
Sorry.
对不起
Did you take a bath, Ichiko?
小一 你洗澡了吗？
Yes. Two days ago.
洗了 前天洗的
Wait, do I smell?
怎么 有味道？
No, you're still good.
不 现在还没有
What do you want to do on the 22nd?
22号那天 你想做什么？
The 22nd?
22号？
-Why? -It's our anniversary.
-为什么？ -是结婚纪念日
Our seventh year of marriage.
我们结婚七周年了
Where should we go?
该去哪儿好呢？
Barbecue? Sushi? Italian?
吃烤肉？寿司？意大利餐？
I think I can take that day off.
我那天应该可以请假
But anyway,
比起那个
this site I'm making for women is all about marriage.
我正在做的这个针对女性的网站 全是关于婚姻的内容
Your leg. That's improper.
腿别这么放哦
Yes.
好
The survey of married couples is a disaster.
已婚人士的调查结果惨不忍睹
For the question of "What kind of existence is your husband?",
问她们 “丈夫是怎样的存在？”
"Less than a pet" was actually quite decent.
回答“不如宠物”都算好的
Some answered with "carbon dioxide," "ATM," and even "moth."
有回答说 “二氧化碳” “自动提款机” 甚至还有“蛾子”
Really?
真的呀？
And it's common to not even talk to their spouse for three days.
夫妻之间三天不说话 都是家常便饭
Isn't it a living hell to live with so much dissatisfaction and scorn?
这种充满怨言和鄙视的日子 难道不像地狱吗？
It's a contract they entered of their own free will…
明明是在你情我愿的基础上 建立的契约…
UNHAPPY COUPLES DON'T CELEBRATE WEDDING ANNIVERSARIES
（婚姻不幸福的夫妇 不庆祝结婚纪念日）
…so, why would they want to stay married like that?
…为什么还要维系这样的婚姻？
As a third party, you can't really know what their relationship is like.
别人的家事 外人哪搞得清
Otoyan.
二也
-Yeah? -That.
-嗯？ -那个
What's the round thing in this week's arrangement?
这周的花 上面圆圆的东西是什么？
Kumquat.
金桔
That thing for bug bites?
治蚊虫叮咬那个？
I like it. It's cute.
真不错 好可爱
It seems kumquats have nothing to do with the kinkan for bug bites.
貌似和蚊虫叮咬的那个 “金桔药膏”是两码事
What?
什么？
They say it means "gratitude" in the flower language.
据说它的花语是“感恩”
I see.
这样啊
Thanks.
谢谢
It's weird to say it myself,
虽然自己说这种话 好像有点奇怪
but we…
但我们…
probably have a pretty happy marriage.
应该算是模范夫妻
Okay. Give me one.
好 给我一个
Here you go.
给你
BASED ON THE MANGA "1122" BY PEKO WATANABE
（根据渡边平子同名漫画改编）
1122: FOR A HAPPY MARRIAGE
电视剧名：1122 好夫妻
MIDORI OSTEOPATHY
（绿色整骨）
To summarize the concept you want,
那我来总结一下 您的要求就是
the website for Midori Osteopathy
绿色整骨的网站设计
should focus on a warm and friendly design.
应该给人一种温暖亲切的感觉
Yes, exactly.
是的
I really want to say
我最想表达的意思就是
that you should catch the message your own body is sending you.
要抓住自己的身体所发出的信息
Especially to the younger generation.
特别是现在的年轻人
The bodies of women like you who are too busy working are
比如你这样的女性 工作太忙
crying in pain due to the stress.
压力太大 身体都在哭泣
You feel it, right?
你懂我意思吧？
Your face is so pale, your eyes are dull and have no spark.
你脸色苍白 双眼黯淡无光
Really?
是吗？
Excuse me for a moment.
恕我冒昧
Your pulse is weak.
你的脉象很弱
And your fingers are cold.
手指冰凉
It's covered by makeup, but aren't your dark circles permanent?
虽然化妆遮住了 但黑眼圈常年不消吧？
You're stagnating.
你这是血气郁结
With your job, you're always looking at the computer, right?
因为工作的关系 你总是盯着电脑吧？
And you're all hunched over.
驼着个背
The blood flow to your pelvis is sluggish,
骨盆血液运行不畅
so your womb and lower body will be chilled.
所以子宫和下半身会发寒
It'll also affect your mental state. It really isn't good.
这还会影响你的精神状态
Are you eating breakfast properly?
你有好好吃早饭吗？
Yes, kind of.
还行吧
You're probably only eating cold food straight out of the fridge.
冰箱里的冷饭冷菜 你大概拿出来就直接吃
The squid ink dish is really good.
墨鱼好好吃哦
Yeah, it is.
对 好好吃
-I like it. -'Cause the dashi is different.
-我喜欢 -因为汤不一样
-Here's your order. -Still--
-您的饮料来了 -尽管如此…
Thank you.
谢谢
Aren't you drinking too fast, Keikei?
惠惠 你会不会喝得太快了？
Listen. My house is almost done.
听好了 我的房子有着落了
Nice! The special custom-order home in the middle of Tokyo everyone wants.
太好了 让人趋之若鹜的 东京市中心特别定制房
If it was only for the two of us.
如果就我们两人住 确实是很好
You'll be living with your mother-in-law?
你要和婆婆一起住？
Yeah. Now every time I see her, she'll say, "You can have kids anytime
是啊 这下每次见面她都会说 “现在家里地方大了
now that our house has more space."
什么时候要个孩子吧”
As if that will happen! We aren't having sex at all.
你让我怎么要！最近根本都没有做爱
The egg and sperm can't even meet.
精子和卵子根本见不了面
Is she saying a stork is going to deliver a baby
难道她觉得小宝宝是送子鸟叼来的？
or one will come out of a peach like Momotaro?
还是像桃太郎一样 从桃子里蹦出来不成？
A no-sex conception?
处女怀胎？
"No-sex conception"?
“处女怀胎”？
What? Am I Saint Mary?
你当我是圣母玛丽亚吗？
She gives me silk stomach warmers, telling me to keep my uterus warm.
她送了我真丝的暖腹带 说是要给子宫保暖
If she wants to see her grandkids so badly,
这么想抱孙子的话
then she should be giving her son Cialis or Viagra.
就该给儿子吃点壮阳药呀
So, medication is required?
这么说 他没药不行咯？
Yes. He is ED.
对 他阳痿
-Oh, my God. -Yes, yes.
-天呐 -对
And you, Ichiko? Still doing it?
一子你呢？还在做吗？
No.
没有
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的？ -嗯
What about you, Tama?
你呢 小玉？
It's been three months since I gave birth, so we're waiting for the vulva to heal.
我生完孩子才三个月 还在等下面恢复
Get well soon.
祝你早日康复
-But can I ask a question? -Go ahead.
-我能问个问题吗？ -问吧
What about your sex drive? How do you deal with it?
你们的性欲呢？是怎么处理的？
All of a sudden?
这么突然？
I want to know.
我很好奇
-Can I go first? -Of course.
-我先来可以吗？ -请吧
As you all know,
你们都知道
-I have Okamura-chan and… -We know.
-我有冈村大叔和… -我们知道
Okamura-chan and, I guess, my dog.
冈村大叔 还有我的狗狗
Dog?
狗？
I get Okamura-chan, but…
冈村大叔我能理解 但…
Affection and lust are very similar.
爱和性很相似
I can fulfill my need for sex if I shower my love onto something.
所以如果能在某处倾注爱意 那性欲也能得到满足
I have a baby, so I can understand.
这我懂 因为我有小孩
-Right? -Yeah.
-对吧？ -对
But sex is sex.
但性就是性
I don't want to stop having sex after getting married.
我不想结婚以后性生活归零
That's true.
那倒是
And you, Ichiko?
你呢 一子？
Well, my sex drive
我的性欲嘛
has always been a calm sea.
一直风平浪静的
Calm sea?
风平浪静？
What's a calm sea?
这是什么意思？
Like a quiet and peaceful water surface.
就像平静无波的水面
With barely a breeze. Sometimes a small stimulation creates a ripple effect,
几乎一丝风都没有 偶尔会因为 细微刺激 泛起一点涟漪
but it gets quietly absorbed back into the water.
但很快就会被水面吞没了
Ichiko's sex drive is very poetic.
一子的性欲真有诗意
But what about Otoya? Is he okay with your calm sea?
那二也呢？ 你风平浪静 他不介意吗？
Yeah. So far.
目前还好吧
-What was that? -You hesitated.
-什么情况？ -你犹豫了
-I thought I hit a nerve. -Sorry, sorry. It didn't mean anything.
-我还以为说到你的痛处了 -对不起 并没有特别的意思
You scared me.
你吓到我了
But don't men have a lot of solutions? Like going to brothels?
但男人们不是有很多解决途径嘛？ 比如去风俗馆？
-Yeah. -It's harder for women.
-对 -女人就没那么容易了
My coworker told me about a secret beauty salon.
我的同事告诉我 有这么一家地下美容院
What do you mean? What's that?
怎么讲？什么地方？
It's a salon Miss A, a friend of my coworker, goes to.
我同事甲小姐经常去那里
It's a little expensive, but it has rave reviews.
价钱小贵 但好评如潮
There's a special massage that is a secret option for members.
那儿有一项只面对会员的 秘密按摩服务
She said it's actually a brothel for women.
她说那里其实就是个 为女性服务的风俗馆
No way!
不会吧
No way. Isn't that just an urban legend?
不会吧 那不就是个都市传传说吗？
But Miss A actually went and said it was so good she fell in love with it.
但甲小姐真去了 而且说特别舒服 让她欲罢不能
So, how far do they go in that brothel?
那他们会做到哪一步？
Right? Don't you want to know?
对吧？你们不想知道吗？
It's categorized as a massage, so the general rule is
这算是按摩项目 所以基本的规则就是
they won't go all the way. But I hear there are people who beg for it.
不会真做到底 但我听说 有人苦苦哀求人家继续
No way. They beg?
不是吧 还哀求？
They're very selective of the male therapists,
他们的男按摩师都经过精挑细选
so they have avid fans.
所以颇有一批死忠
Seriously?
真的呀？
What's the name of the place?
那地方叫什么名字？
I think it was Eden?
好像是叫“伊甸园”？
Eden.
伊甸园
-Like paradise. -Paradise?
-就像天堂 -天堂？
-Or was it Flower Garden? Benzaiten? -Hey!
-还是“花园”来着？拜占庭？ -喂！
It can't be Benzaiten. What's with your memory?
不可能叫“拜占庭” 瞧你这记性
But are you okay with it? With your husband going to a brothel?
但老公去逛风俗馆 你们不介意吗？
What do you married ladies say?
你们几个有夫之妇怎么说？
I think it's like a pseudo-romance.
我觉得这就像一种伪爱情
If it gives him some relief and joy,
如果能让男人感到慰藉和欢喜
it could actually make our marriage better.
那就对我们的夫妻关系有利无害
-It adds some spice. -Yeah, like spicing up the relationship.
-增添情趣 -对 为夫妻生活增添情趣
It's much better than an affair with real feelings.
比起动了真感情的婚外情可好多了
Right.
对呀
Better than what Atsushi did.
比五代做的那档事好多了
You had to say it.
你非要说出来
Atsushi Godai?
五代敦史？
-Yeah. -What happened with him?
-对 -他怎么了？
You don't know? It was a while ago.
你不知道吗？是挺久前的事了
I don't. What did he do?
我不知道 他怎么了？
He had an affair.
他搞外遇
Did he? Well, he seems really popular.
是吗？他是挺有人缘的
But it's not exactly surprising, is it?
但这也算是意料之中吧？
Was being sexless the cause?
是因为没有性生活吗？
I don't know that much.
具体我就不知道了
Right. Anyway, we wouldn't know.
对 外人哪知道
-Not like you can ask. -Why did I even ask?
-这种事又不好多问 -我为什么还要问？
I see.
对哦
-That could be the reason. -Right?
-有可能是因为这个 -对吧？
Since when was it a calm sea?
风平浪静多久了？
A year ago?
一年？
No, two years?
不 两年？
The last time I had sex was…
上次做还是…
Good morning.
早上好
Did you drink a lot?
喝了很多酒吗？
Just a normal amount.
没有很多
I can't drink as much anymore. Since I'm getting old.
因为我上了年纪 酒量没有以前好了
-Apparently… -Yeah?
-话说… -嗯？
…I'm sluggish and stagnating.
…有人说我缺乏活力 血气郁结
And my eyes are dull.
还说我双眼无光
Who said that?
谁说的？
My client. She's an osteopathic therapist.
我的客户 是个整骨师
Isn't she mean?
是不是很过分？
Very mean.
太过分了
Here, drink some water.
来 喝点水
Thanks.
谢谢
So, Otoyan,
对了 二也
want to go to a hot spring for our anniversary? And stay the night?
结婚纪念日想去泡温泉吗？ 然后在那边住一晚？
Wow, great idea.
好主意
I'll be late today, so make sure to lock the door.
我今天回来得晚 千万别忘了锁门
-It's Flower Day? -Yeah.
-今天是花日吗？ -对
Got it.
知道了
And if you feel like it, eat the simmered lotus root in the fridge. Or it'll go bad.
冰箱里的炖莲藕 饿了就吃吧 快到保质期了
Okay.
好
I'm off.
我出门了
Have a good day.
路上小心
That quilting…
那件外套
He wore his favorite one.
是他最喜欢的
MISS RUKI BY FUMIKO TAKANO
（《留希小姐》 高野文子著）
Thursdays are Otoyan's Flower Days.
每周四是二也的花日
And today, the third Thursday of the month,
而今天 每个月的第三个周四
is when he spends the night with his lover.
是他和情人一起过夜的日子
Someone in our family is in love.
我们家有人恋爱了
You scared me.
吓我一跳
Good morning.
早上好
Do you want breakfast, Ichiko?
想吃早餐吗 小一？
I'll eat later.
我晚点再吃
The salmon…
这三文鱼…
A person in love is always blissfully shining.
恋爱中的人总是散发出幸福的光
This rice has a perfect texture.
这米饭的口感真好
I'm really good at making rice.
我真是太会煮饭了
Or is it because it's the first crop?
还是说 因为这是新米？
The rice cooker did the actual cooking.
其实煮饭的是电饭锅
He's in a really good mood.
他心情真好
I grilled a salmon for you.
我帮你也煎了一份三文鱼
And so considerate.
真体贴
Like he's truly alive.
整个人生气勃勃
Is this what they mean by "glowing"?
这就是所谓的“容光焕发”吗？
Do you have plans tonight?
你今晚有什么安排吗？
I plan to work leisurely. And there's one meeting.
我打算忙点儿工作 然后还要见客户
Want to eat out? Let's go to that Japanese place you were interested in.
想出去吃饭吗？我们就去 你感兴趣的那家日式餐厅吧
Good idea. I'll make the reservation. What time?
好呀 我来预约 几点？
I'll see how things go and let you know.
我看情况通知你
Okay.
好的
So, it gives relief and joy, and could make our marriage
如果能让人感到慰藉和欢喜 那对夫妻关系…
better?
有利无害？
This is so good. It makes me happy.
太好吃了 真开心
This place looks nice, right?
这地方看起来真不错 对吧？
Yeah.
对
Pardon.
久等了
Here you are. This is the sashimi.
这是两位的刺身
This is sea bream, tuna and bigfin reef squid.
鲷鱼、金枪鱼和大尾鱿鱼
-Thank you.
-谢谢
-Bigfin reef squid. -Sea bream.
-大尾鱿鱼 -鲷鱼
-Delicious. -Yeah.
-真好吃 -嗯
Delicious.
好吃
For the 22nd,
22号的安排
I found a nice place in Hakone.
我在箱根找到一个不错的地方
This one.
就是这里
It's an auberge, and the hot spring looks really nice.
是一家小旅馆 温泉看起来很不错
REVIEWS
（评分 4.87星）
The reviews are really good. See?
评分很高吧？
So I made a reservation.
我已经预定好了
-Ichiko. -Yeah?
-小一 -嗯？
Can we go the week after instead?
可以往后挪一周吗？
What? Why?
嗯？为什么？
Well…
那个…
You have a date?
约会？
Yeah.
嗯
Why? It's not a Thursday.
为什么？又不是周四
She had a conflict.
她那边有点事
What conflict?
有什么事？
With her family and stuff.
家里有事什么的
What? Family?
哈？家里有事？
Don't go, "What?"
别说“哈”啊
No. It is a "What?" kind of situation.
我就要说 这种事就该“哈”吧？
She has a family matter? Of course I'll go, "What?"
她家里有事？我当然要“哈”啦
Then what am I? I am your family, you know.
这样一来我算什么？ 我才是你的家人吧
Is our family less important than hers?
我们家的事就不如她家的重要？
That's not it.
不是这样的
Sorry, that was rude of me.
对不起 是我不应该
Hey, Otoyan, aren't you getting sloppy these days?
二也 你最近是不是 有点太不注意了？
It's like you're on top of the world.
一副得意忘形的样子
You realize you're giving off vibes of pure bliss?
恋爱的气场都外泄了 你自己没感觉吗？
You have this longing look whenever you look at your phone.
还经常对着手机 露出一脸憧憬的样子
Really?
真的吗？
Didn't you promise
你不是答应过
not to bring your extracurricular romance into our home?
不把外面的恋情带到家里来的吗？
You're not breaking the rules, are you?
你不会违反规则吧？
You're right.
你说得对
Sorry, Ichiko. I'll be more careful.
对不起 小一 我下次注意
Let me make it clear. I'm not being jealous.
我可说清楚 我不是吃醋
I know.
我知道
And I'm not being resentful. This isn't about emotions, but the rules.
我也不是心怀愤恨 这和情感无关 是规则问题
I understand.
我明白
Sorry. I'll make sure to fix the 22nd.
对不起 22号我会重新安排的
Okay.
好
Then this talk is over.
那这就谈完了
This one is really good.
这个特别好吃
Wow.
哇塞！
Hot spring.
温泉
ELECASA NO YU
（埃莱卡萨温泉）
Auberge.
旅馆
This isn't jealousy.
我不是嫉妒
It isn't,
不是嫉妒
but an itchy, dark feeling is causing ripples in my calm sea.
但有种痒痒的、阴暗的感觉 在我风平浪静的水面激起了涟漪
I'm certain of it.
肯定是这样
Found it.
找到了
SHORT INTENSIVE 7-DAY DIET
（比利的健身营 短期集中7日饮食法）
We'll be doing cardio for ten minutes.
我们来做10分钟有氧运动吧
Let's warm up your body. Count!
来做热身运动 数数！
Work it. Go. Go.
努力动起来
Now spin.
现在转圈
Come on.
来
Spin. Spin.
转 继续转
Focus from the top of your head to the bottom of your feet in this warm up.
热身时 从头顶到脚底 集中注意力
Here we go. Now raise your arms.
很好 现在举起手臂
Tap to the left.
左边拍一下
You're a butterfly now. Tap your toes. Let's count.
现在你成了一只蝴蝶 踮脚踏步
Work it. Go.
来数数
Tap. Tap!
拍 再拍
One more time.
再来一次
-Wow. This is amazing. -Wow.
-好棒哦 -哇
What a beautiful auberge.
这旅馆真漂亮
-It is. -Right?
-真漂亮 -是吧？
This is amazing.
太棒了
-Beautiful, right? -It's gorgeous, right?
-真美 对吧？ -太美了吧？
I'm getting excited.
我好期待哦
Otoyan.
二也
Thank you.
谢谢你
For what?
为什么？
For this trip
为这次旅行
and everything in our seven years of marriage.
还有过去七年婚姻中的一切
We both did our part.
这里面有我们双方的付出
To many more years to come.
以后的日子里还请多多关照
To many more years.
请多多关照
That was a good bath.
泡得好舒服哦
Welcome back.
你回来啦
I'm back.
我回来了
Wow, Otoyan.
二也
Your skin is so smooth.
你的皮肤好光滑哦
'Cause
因为…
I went in the hot spring.
我泡了温泉啊
And you smell really good.
你身上也好香
Really?
是吗？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
You're so stiff.
身体这么僵硬
Ichiko.
小一
Let's relax.
我们来放松一下吧
Ichiko!
小一！
Ouch.
好疼
Sorry.
对不起
My husband hurt me.
我被老公弄疼了
Sorry, Ichiko. Are you okay?
对不起 小一 你没事吧？
Not only did you refuse to have sex, I also hit my head. This hurts.
你不仅拒绝和我亲热 还让我撞到头 我好痛
Ichiko.
小一
I'll post it on my socials and ask everyone to repost it.
我要发到朋友圈 让大家转发
Ichiko. Put on your robe.
小一 把衣服穿好
He said I'm ugly.
我老公说我丑
No, I didn't.
我没有
Then why did you reject me with all your might? We're married.
那你为什么拼命拒绝我？明明是夫妻
Ichiko.
小一
You know I have someone I like, right?
你知道我有喜欢的人吧？
Yeah.
知道
I know. So, what?
我知道 所以呢？
Wait, so I'm not the one Otoyan likes?
话说 难道我就不是 二也喜欢的人吗？
I like Ichiko too.
我也喜欢小一
Then you can have sex with me.
那和我亲热有什么关系
It's not like you'll lose anything.
你又不会少块肉
I will.
会的
You will?
会吗？
Ichiko.
小一
Do you remember when we stopped having sex?
我们什么时候开始不亲热的 你还记得吗？
I remember. Generally.
记得个大概吧
Even what you said to me?
你当时对我说的话呢？
Otoyan.
二也
Sorry.
抱歉
I've been so tired lately.
我最近太累了
So I don't really…
所以不是太想…
I see.
我知道了
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's okay.
没事
That's not how it went.
才不是这样
That's not what I said?
我不是这么说的吗？
It's not.
不是的
It was like this.
是这样的
Otoyan.
二也
Actually,
那个…
I can't bring myself
我最近
to do it these days.
做不来这种事
You mean you're feeling sick?
你身体不舒服吗？
No. My body is fine,
没有 身体没事
but I can't get in the mood for things like sex.
但做爱什么的 我没那个心情
Can't get in the mood?
没心情？
Is that the truth?
真是这样吗？
Otoyan, the two of us
二也 我们两个
get along really well,
关系这么好
and have no problem communicating,
言语交流起来完全没问题
so do we really need it? Sex?
所以我们不做也没关系吧？
Since we're a family.
都是一家人了
I want to do it.
可就算是家人
Even if we're family.
我还是想做
I see.
这样啊
Then how about going to a brothel?
那去风俗馆怎么样？
Can't you satisfy your urges outside the house?
在外面解决生理需要不行吗？
I'm really sorry about that.
真的很抱歉
Plus it's not like you're not popular with the ladies.
再说了 你也不是没有女人缘
Wasn't I horrible?
我是不是很过分？
That's what I'm saying.
我就说啊 真的很过分
You didn't make it worse
该不会是因为虚假记忆 或者理解偏差
with distorted or false memories?
所以导致比实际情况更糟糕？
Definitely not.
绝对不是
I remember it very clearly.
我记得一清二楚
It should've been just sex.
本来仅仅是性爱而已
But our relationship became more complicated
可我却因为怕麻烦 就选择回避
as I ignored it just because I found it annoying.
结果却让我们的关系变得更加复杂
Otoyan.
二也
Hug me.
抱抱我
Is this the boomerang effect?
这就叫弄巧成拙吗？
Okay, then please change the color of the top page
好了 那就把首页的颜色改一下
and make the covers on the new release page stand out more.
然后再把新发布页面的封页 做得更醒目一点
Understood.
知道了
I'll e-mail you later about the schedule and fee.
截止日期和酬劳我晚点发给你
Sure. Thanks.
好的 谢了
Thank you so much!
多谢啦
Thank you.
谢谢
We're getting positive feedback about the site you made.
你制作的网站反馈不错
Really? That's good to know.
真的吗？好开心
You gave a boring horticulture magazine site a pop of personality.
托你的福 平淡的园艺杂志 也有了一丝时尚感
It's easier to read it now.
现在浏览起来更方便了
Well, it's the same for me.
我才是
I didn't have a lot of projects this month. You saved me.
这个月接的活儿不多 你帮了我大忙
Really? I thought you were busy.
是吗？我还以为你很忙呢
No.
没有啦
I'm barely getting by.
勉强凑合而已
Ichiko, is everything okay?
一子 你没事吧？
You seem a little down.
有点无精打采的样子
-You can tell? -Yeah.
-你能看出来？ -嗯
Keikei.
惠惠
Can you hear me out?
能听我说说吗？
So it's serious.
看来很严重嘛
Go ahead.
说吧
Actually…
是这样的…
Permission to have extramarital romance?
婚外恋许可制？
Yeah.
对
In other words, Otoya is having an authorized affair?
也就是说 你默许二也搞外遇？
I guess you can say it like that.
可以这么说吧
I never knew.
从没听你说过
I never told anyone. I thought you'd be repulsed.
我谁也没告诉 怕你们觉得排斥
I'm not repulsed by it.
我不会觉得排斥
But
不过
I thought it was a reasonable solution.
我之前觉得这样安排挺合理的
Be a family at home and enjoy love outside.
在家过日子 在外面谈恋爱
Don't say it like bean throwing for Setsubun.
别说得像迎春撒豆子去邪纳福一样
When did it start?
什么时候开始的？
About a year ago, I think.
有一年了吧
A year.
一年
About the time when that outside love is gushing out dopamine.
婚外情的多巴胺喷发期啊
Yeah, it looks like he's in a state of bliss.
是啊 一副乐陶陶的样子
Looks like?
是吧？
Is his lover someone you know?
那小三你认识吗？
No.
不认识
You know…
其实…
the night I rejected Otoyan's advances for sex,
那晚 我拒绝了二也的求欢
it felt like I heard his heart breaking.
感觉好像听到了他心碎的声音
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome back.
你回来啦
I felt guilty when I saw Otoyan looking a little sad.
看到二也难过的样子 我有些自责
And it was right when I started freelancing and had so much work.
那时我刚开始做自由职业 有一大堆工作
But in the end, I found it too annoying to deal with.
但最终 我嫌太麻烦 于是就这么不了了之
When sex sunk to the bottom of the ocean of our marriage,
当性淹没在婚姻的海洋中时
right when peaceful days returned
我们之间恢复了平静 仿佛从一开始就没出现过问题
like we never had any issues…
就在这时…
Ichiko.
小一
I'll be late today, so go to bed first.
我今天晚点回来 你先睡吧
Okay.
好
I'm off.
我出门啦
Have a good day.
路上小心
…Otoyan started taking
…二也开始下班之后
ikebana classes after work.
学习花道
He was becoming happier day by day.
他的心情变得越来越好
So when I finally confirmed it,
当我终于确认时
he had already stopped looking at me.
他已经不再看我了
Hey, Otoyan.
二也
Do you have
你是不是有了
someone you like?
喜欢的人？
Is it mutual?
她也喜欢你吗？
Maybe.
可能吧
Sorry.
对不起
I was shocked.
我非常震惊
But I thought I had no right to be shocked.
但我觉得自己无权感到震惊
It's okay.
不
It's not something you should apologize for.
这不是你的错
I was the one who said
当初是我说你有女人缘
you're quite popular, and that you should find someone outside.
让你去外面找人的
You don't need to apologize or hide it.
你不必道歉 也不必瞒着我
Don't you hate lying?
你不是最讨厌撒谎吗？
Instead,
与其那样
let's set some rules.
不如来定几条规则吧
Rules?
规则？
What's good?
定什么规则好呢？
You don't have to lie or hide it,
你不用撒谎隐瞒 但在家时
but don't let it show at home.
不可以表露出来
And I won't pry either.
我也不会打探你的事
What else?
还有什么呢？
This was the result.
之所以变成这样
The result of me not making an effort to meet Otoyan's desires.
是因为我没有努力满足二也的渴望
So I decided.
所以这一次
I won't ignore his feelings this time.
我下定决心 不会忽略他的感受
And are you okay with that?
你不会介意吗？
I thought I was.
原本以为不会
But lately, I've been feeling uneasy.
但最近感觉有点焦虑
Of course you would.
那当然咯
You're human. You'll have feelings about it.
你也是人啊 也有感情的
I thought the trust and respect we have for each other
我原本觉得比起一时的情欲
was more important than a temporary moment of lust.
我们彼此间的信任和尊重才更加重要
Maybe I was naive.
或许是我太天真了
You can't underestimate the passion, assumptions and emotional highs of love.
即便热恋的激情、盲目和亢奋
Even if it is all an illusion created by the mind.
是大脑创造的幻觉 也不能小瞧啊
People have self-destructed, gone crazy, and died due to those illusions.
因为这些幻觉而堕落发狂 丢掉性命的大有人在
No, I don't want that.
我可不想那样
-We took a small trip for our anniversary. -Yeah.
-之前去旅行庆祝结婚纪念日 -嗯
Spent a night at a hot spring.
在温泉旅馆住了一晚
That night, he rejected me.
那天晚上 他拒绝了我
Why?
为什么？
He said, "You know I have someone I like, right?"
他说：“你知道我有喜欢的人吧？”
What? Is that how it'll be?
他这么说吗？
So you two won't be having sex as long as he's having an affair?
所以说 只要他在外面有人 你们之间就不会有性爱？
I think that's how it'll be. Right?
应该是吧
But we get along really well.
但我们相处得非常好
Aren't things getting complicated?
这样岂不是搞得很复杂？
Then what about your calm sea?
你的风平浪静呢？
Are you feeling any waves?
有没有感觉到风浪呢？
Then it's not a calm sea anymore.
不再是风平浪静了啊
But
可是
if we'll be sexless for my entire life,
如果余生都要做无性夫妻
then that's kind of lonely.
感觉挺孤单的
But doesn't that permission to have an extramarital romance
但那套婚外恋许可制
also apply to you?
对你就不适用吗？
It was a joke. A joke.
我开玩笑的 玩笑而已
This is definitely going to be tasty.
肯定会很好吃
Yeah.
是啊
Shrimp, perilla leaves and lotus root?
虾仁、紫苏 还有莲藕？
Yeah. And this one is
对 这个是
pork, cilantro and bamboo shoots.
猪肉、香菜和竹笋
-That's a good sound.
-真好听
I'm going to try this one.
我来尝尝这个
Isn't the bamboo good?
竹笋很好吃吧？
-It gives it a good texture. -Yeah.
-口感很好 -嗯
-This one's a hit.
-这个馅的好吃
-But… -Ichiko is a genius.
-但… -小一太厉害了
I am, aren't I? I can't pick which one's better.
厉害吧？这两种不相上下
This one's good too.
这个也很好吃
-The shrimp is yummy too. -Really.
-虾仁的也好吃 -确实
Your phone is ringing.
你电话响了
Yeah. It's okay.
没关系
Do you want the last shrimp dumpling?
最后一个虾仁的你要吗？
No. It's fine. I'm full.
不了 我吃饱了
Thanks for the meal.
我吃饱了
You're welcome.
好
Hello, Mitsuki?
喂？美月
I was eating dinner.
我在吃晚饭
It was dumplings. And you?
吃的煎饺 你呢？
But doesn't that permission to have an extramarital romance
但那套婚外恋许可制
also apply to you?
对你就不适用吗？
It's true that it also applies to me.
确实对我也适用
But
可是
if both the husband and wife did it,
如果夫妻双方都这样
what would be the point of us
那么维持这段婚姻
staying married?
还有什么意义？
Welcome.
欢迎光临
-Atsushi. -It's been a while.
-五代君 -好久不见
Long time no see. Sorry to ask you out.
好久不见 抱歉 突然叫你出来
No worries. I'll always accept your invitation.
没关系 你的邀约我随时奉陪
Where should I sit? There?
我坐哪儿？那边？
Oh, right, Ichiko.
对了 一子
A special exhibit starting this month at my museum.
我的博物馆这个月开始有个特别展
He's a young artist making things like these.
是一位年轻的艺术家 这些是他的作品
So pretty.
好漂亮
I thought you'd like it.
我就想着你会喜欢
Why don't you come see it?
来参观一下吧？
Sure. I will.
好 我会的
Can I order?
可以点东西吃了吗？
Of course.
当然
Do you have any bar snacks?
你们这儿有什么酒吧小吃吗？
Yes.
有的
We have dry fruits…
我们有果干…
Dry fruits.
果干
-…and mixed nuts. -Mixed nuts sound good.
-…混合坚果 -混合坚果貌似不错
Atsushi and I were in the same art club in college.
我和五代君大学时是同一个艺术社的
We've known each other for a long time, and know each other's preferences.
我们认识很久了 也熟悉彼此的喜好
I'm not attracted to him, but he is kind of hot.
我对他并不来电 但他长得还挺帅
We probably both like each other in a broad sense of the word.
或许从广义上讲 我们对彼此都颇有好感
His looks and our relationship
从颜值和交情来看
make him qualified.
他是合适的人选
So, what's going on?
出什么事了？
Since you called me out of the blue.
突然约我出来
I'll be direct and ask.
那我就直说了
Have you ever had an affair?
你有过外遇吗？
-Sorry, sorry. I'm sorry. -Sorry.
-抱歉 -不好意思
I heard about it.
我都听说了
My husband is having one.
我老公也在搞外遇
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的呀？ -真的
And I needed a friend
我需要找一个伙伴
to talk about it with.
一个倾诉的对象
If you say it that way,
这么说来
I'm a friend who had an affair that ended last year.
我倒是个有过外遇的伙伴 去年结束了
So you're Mr. Done With My Affair.
这么说 你的婚外情结束了
Yes.
对
-Here's your order. -Thanks.
-这是您点的 -谢谢
-Actually… -Yeah?
-那个… -嗯？
…she was my classmate from high school.
…对方是我高中同学
From Shizuoka.
静冈同乡
We met again due to work,
因为工作的关系又遇到她
and kept bumping into each other.
之后总是碰巧撞见
One time,
有一次
we were both reading the same book on the train.
我们在火车上看同一本书
I was so surprised.
我简直惊呆了
That is surprising.
确实很巧
We had the same hobbies,
我们有相同的爱好
and I had so much fun just talking to her.
和她聊天 我觉得非常开心
They believe their own past loves are special and unique.
他们觉得曾经的恋情 是与众不同的特殊存在
I wondered if my fated love wasn't my wife,
我就想 或许我的真命天女 不是我老婆
but this woman instead.
而是这个女人
These cheating men really spew a whole load of bullshit
这些出轨的男人真是满嘴屁话
in a sad and romantic manner.
既可悲 又浪漫
Since she wanted to get married and have kids…
因为她想要结婚 要小孩…
I thought Otoyan was different,
我原以为二也和他们不同
but maybe I was wrong?
或许我错了？
…shouldn't
…不应该
waste any more of her life.
再继续耽误她的人生
A sleazebag of a friend.
无耻下流的伙伴
Which makes him perfect.
所以他正合适
Hey, Atsushi.
五代君
Want to go to a hotel after this?
等会儿想去酒店开房吗？
Me?
我吗？
What's wrong?
你怎么了？
Are you okay? I didn't think you'd be in so much pain.
你还好吧？我没想到你会这么痛苦
No, that's not it.
不是的
I'm ready to go.
我很想去
To be honest,
老实说
I thought, "Wow. For real? Lucky, yay."
我刚心里想 “哇塞 这也太幸运了吧”
"Yay?"
“哇塞”？
However…
但是…
However.
“但是”
…it's dangerous for me right now.
目前对我而言 太危险了
What? How creepy.
什么呀？好奇怪
I'm not bluffing.
我不是吓唬你
That affair I was talking about,
我刚不是说之前有外遇嘛
it ended when my wife found out.
最后被我老婆发现了
What? You made it sound
什么？你刚说得好像
like you ended things neatly.
是你自己主动结束的一样
I skipped over some details.
我省略了一些细节
After that, she's been spying on me.
从那之后 我老婆一直在监视我
She knows everywhere I've been to in a single day
我每天去过哪些地方 她都一清二楚
in real time.
能实时定位
What?
啊？
-Right? Isn't it scary? -Yeah.
-是不是很吓人？ -嗯
Isn't that dangerous?
是不是很危险？
She probably put
她可能在我身上
one of those professional GPS trackers
放了某种卫星定位装置
used by private detectives on me.
私家侦探用的那种
Don't get creeped out.
你别怕
Doesn't that mean she might be listening to our conversation?
所以说 她可能正在听我们说话？
She's not. It's just my location, so far.
不会 目前为止只有定位而已
And she's okay with me seeing my friends.
她不介意我和朋友碰面
Since my work puts me in situations where I'm alone with women a lot.
因为工作的关系 我经常要单独和女性相处
But
但是
if I went to a hotel with a friend, then we'll be sex friends. Right?
如果和朋友去了酒店 那就变成了炮友 对吧？
Then I'd get beaten up.
那我会被打死的
Beaten?
打死？
Up.
死翘翘
My wife has a fifth degree black belt in aikido. In high school,
我老婆是合气道黑带五段 高中时
she twisted the arm of a molester so badly,
有个登徒子被她拧胳膊
he cried.
拧得都哭了
That's a heroic tale.
真是个巾帼英雄
Atsushi.
五代君
You really like your wife.
你真的很爱你老婆
Me? You think so?
是吗？你这么想？
You do. You know it too, don't you?
对 你心里有数 对吧？
I wonder.
谁知道啊
I'm not so sure about myself.
我自己说不清
I'm currently
我目前
rebuilding our marriage.
正在重建我的婚姻
So I'm sorry.
所以 对不住了
And one more thing.
还有一件事
I'd really regret it if you and I did
如果我们真的做了那样的事
something like that
破坏了目前的关系
and it destroyed our current relationship.
我会觉得非常可惜的
Don't--
别…
Don't say that while holding my hand.
别握着我的手说这种话
Oops.
哎呦
I want to believe sex wouldn't change anything
我情愿相信单纯的性爱 不会改变任何事
since we're both adults.
毕竟我们都是成年人
But something definitely changes once you do it.
但是一旦那么做了 有些东西就肯定会变
You're right.
你说得对
That's true.
确实如此
Why did you choose me anyway?
话说回来 怎么会选中我？
It was the result of my comprehensive evaluation and assessment.
是做了全面评估得出的结果
Was I the first?
我是首选吗？
Does that have a special meaning?
有特别的意义吗？
No, it felt like it.
没有 随便问问
I see.
这样啊
So it was calculated.
所以是评估的结果
But that still makes me happy.
但我还是很高兴
This is my treat.
今天我请客
-In fact, let me treat you. -Why?
-想吃什么尽管点 -为什么？
But if it's on you, then I'm going to order more.
但既然是你请客 那我就不客气了
Go ahead.
别客气
Do you have other foods?
你们这儿还有别的吃的吗？
I'm home.
我回来了
Welcome back.
你回来啦
Didn't you say you'd be out late?
你不是说要晚回吗？
That's what I thought, but I came home before midnight.
原本是这么以为的 但我不到半夜就回家了
And you? Did you just get home?
你呢？刚到家？
That's a pretty flower.
这花真好看
What's it called?
叫什么名字？
Anthurium.
火鹤花
It means a "heart in agony due to love" in the flower language.
花语是“因爱而痛苦的心”
OTOYA AIHARA WHAT TIME WILL YOU BE HOME?
（相原二也 你什么时候到家？）
STILL, I'LL MAKE THE LAST TRAIN HOME
（还在路上 我搭最后一班车回）
OKAY. DON'T DRINK TOO MUCH
（好 别喝太多）
DIDN'T I SAY YOU WERE SPEWING AN AURA OF PURE BLISS?
（我之前不是说了 你恋爱气场外泄吗？）
AND I DIDN'T EVEN ASK ABOUT THE MEANING OF THE FLOWER.
（而且我又没问你花语是什么）
In my 35th year of life, I fully understand.
都35岁了 我当然懂这个道理
Anger and sadness shouldn't be thrown at your partner.
不该把愤怒和悲伤 发泄在配偶身上
In moments like this, I need to quietly ask myself:
在这种时候 我应该静静地问自己
Ichiko, what do you want to do?
一子 你想做什么？
You scared me.
吓我一跳
Don't look at me like I'm a weirdo.
别用一副看变态的表情看我
Sorry. I was zoning out.
对不起 我刚才走神了
You should also go to bed now too.
你也该去睡觉了
I…
我…
Your period is done, right?
你的生理期结束了吧？
I still have dishes to wash
我还要洗碗
and Hiro's things to prepare for tomorrow.
然后还要准备小宏明天用的东西
You can do that in the morning.
那些事可以明早再做
Hiro's been crying a lot at night.
最近小宏晚上哭得厉害
I'll look after him, so go sleep first.
我去看他 你先睡吧
Mama!
妈妈
Hiro.
小宏
-Mama's here. -Mama!
-妈妈来了 -妈妈
-Come here. -Mama.
-过来
It's okay, Hiro.
没事了 小宏
You don't need to stop crying.
你哭吧 不用停下来
Mama!
妈妈
BEAUTY SALON IN THE CITY - FLOWER GARDEN
（美容院 市内 花园）
SALON FLOWER GARDEN
（花园馆）
WORDS FROM OUR CLIENTS
（顾客评论）
Y.M - BODY EXTRA: THE EXTRA COURSE WAS AMAZING.
（客人YM 美体附加 附加服务太棒了）
I LEARNED SO MUCH ABOUT MY BODY.
（我对自己的身体有了更多了解）
N.T - BODY EXTRA: IT WAS HEAVEN (LOL)
（客人NT 美体附加 妙不可言 笑）
I REGAINED MY CONFIDENCE AS A WOMAN.
（让我重拾身为女性的自信）
T.K - BODY EXTRA: THE MASSEUSE IS A GENIUS.
（客人TK 美体附加 按摩得太舒服了）
ONE SESSION AND I'M A LOYAL CLIENT.
（试过一次就成了忠实顾客）
CONTACT US - RESERVATIONS
（联系我们 预约）
Relief and joy.
慰藉和欢喜
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION.
（本故事纯属虚构）
Subtitle: Annie Chen
字幕翻译：纪小敏